# SARA VAGNARELLI

### **Senior Data Engineer**

saravagnarelli@gmail.com github.com/saravgn

Sydney, NSW, Australia saravagnarelli.com

in linkedin.com/in/engsaravagnarelli/

**\** +61 427 487 300

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Data Engineer Deckard Technologies

Aug 2018 - Present

Sydney, Australia

Deckard Technologies designs and develops analytical reporting systems using modern deep data mining, machine learning, and predictive analytical algorithms to help cities and institutions become smarter

- Wrote AWS CloudFormation scripts to build CodePipelines and stacks for DataMining on Real Estate. AWS-CloudFormation, AWS-CodePipeline for CI/CD, AWS-CodeBuild, AWS-Batch, AWS-GLUE for ETL, AWS-Athena, Selenium, Scrapy, Jinja2, Python, PySpark, OpenVPN, Jira, Github. Created Datadog Dashboard and Alerts through CloudFormation script to analyse AWS-CloudWatch log stream.
- Developed a website that created a unified view of output of the data analytic processes. This has enabled data analysts to quickly evaluate results and prove our algorithms.
   Techstack: Python, Postgres, React, React Router, Redux, Axios,
- Contributed to React Redux Datatable library https://github.com/sean-ww/react-reduxdatatable/graphs/contributors relevant for our purposes.

Flask, Memcache, VSCode, Wireframe, LucidChart.

### Software Engineer

### **Qualcomm ESGDA - Engineering Service Group Data Analytics**

Mov 2016 - May 2018

Sydney, Australia

The Engineering Services Group Data Analytics team builds creative and reliable big data solutions that add value across Qualcomm. These solutions range from but are not limited to wireless communications, intellectual property and financial analysis.

DIRBS - Device Identification and Reporting System http://www.pta.gov.pk/media/dirbs\_cons\_paper\_220616.pdf DIRBS is a large scale system currently running in Pakistan, designed to enable identification and blocking of illegal/counterfeit, cloned or stolen devices running on phone networks.

- Accumulated significant experience in developing performant, efficient Python code, applying a test-driven methodology to guarantee the correctness of the code after modifications
- **Profiling and debugging** of performance related problems both in Python code and in **SQL** database code.
- Development of REST-ful APIs to access information and allow data exchange between multiple components of larger systems (Flask, HTML, CSS)
- Automated regression test suite which exercised 95%+ of the codebase using PyTest and unittest.
- Used **Jenkins** and **Docker** for continuous integration and **Git** for Revision Control.
- Followed an agile methodology including **Sprints** and participation in weekly code reviews. Used **Jira**, **Confluence**.

### **SUMMARY**

I have Bachelor's and Master's Degree in Computer Science and 5 years of working experience as Software Engineer. I enjoy developing and experimenting with new technology and I am focused on finding the best solution for a problem. I am looking for a challenging role that drives change and provides opportunities for career development.

### **EDUCATION**

# M.S. in Computer Engineering Roma Tre University, Italy

**M** Oct 2012 - May 2015

# B.S. in Computer Engineering Roma Tre University, Italy

m Oct 2009 - May 2012

# Deep Learning Nanodegree Udacity

🛗 Jan 2018 - Present

# Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

**Udacity** 

May 2016 - Sept 2016

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

### **Dog-Breed Classifier**

github.com/saravgn/dogbreedclassifier Designed and trained a CNN to identify dog breeds. Applied Transfer Learning to improve the model. **Keras, NumPy, VGG-16, ResNet-50, Scikit-learn** 

Sentiment Classification github.com/saravgn/sentimentclassifier Predict sentiment from movie reviews. NumPy, Scikit-Learn

Predicting Bike Sharing Data github.com/saravgn/bikesharingpred Built and trained a Neural Network from scratch to predict the number of bike-share users on a given day. NumPy

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Consultant / Software Engineer

### **Accenture**

math Sep 2015 - Apr 2016

Rome, Italy

Ministry of Economy and Finance - Indoor Navigation System
Joined Accenture as a graduate software engineer. My first role was as a
part of a consulting team working with the Italian MEF (Ministry of
Economy and Finance) developing an Indoor Navigation System this
included producing a feasibility study evaluating cost and time

### Member of in-house software development team

Joined in-house software development team working in Java and SQL for a variety of clients. My role was primarily optimising in-house process including coordinating testing activities and automating processes execution

# \_\_\_\_\_

### Software Engineering Intern

## New York University

Mov 2014 - May 2015

New York, NY, USA

Conducted a joint research project with Full Professor Chee Yap on autonomous navigation and mapping in GPS-denied environments

- Designed and developed an algorithm for drones quadcopter on using the onboard monocular camera to automatically build a reliable map of the area in which the drone is flying. VISUAL SLAM.
- Designed and developed image processing APIs in C/C++ for objects recognition and used OpenCV (Open Source Computer Vision Library)

-----

# Software Engineering Intern

Roma Tre University

Dec 2011 - May 2012

Rome, Italy

Designed and implemented software for the **geolocation** of radar maps in order to individuate the composition of the underground using **Android** platform

# Communication Github Gontrol Gontrol

# CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- SheHacks-Sydney 2019: Awarded for Best DataScience App https://www.linkedin.com/in/engsaravagnarelli/dactivity/
- CLOUDERA, Data Analyst Fundamentals of data ETL (extract, transform, load), ingestion, and processing with Hadoop tools and how Pig, Hive, and Impala improve productivity for typical analysis tasks.
- C++ programming course
- Academic Language Certificates
   English: TOEFL-IELTS-PTE-BULATS-FIRST-KET-PET.

   Spanish: DELE Cervantes, Camino Barcelona

### LANGUAGES/HOBBIES

- 3D printing ED-209
- Arduino 4-wheel Robot
- Amazon AWS Dash Buttons

### English, Italian Spanish



**Team:** Volleyball, Dance, Karate **Instruments:** Piano and Flute